

DAVID GOMES

— About Me —

About two years ago I was working in a factory but I've always felt like I could do more. I heard of 42 Lisboa and decided to check it out because I've always been passionate about computers. This was my introduction to programming and it filled me with will to, one day, see my contributions live in the world.

42 has a gamified peer-based learning system which creates an agile coding environment and collaborative learning.

While I'm still finishing my last project, I'm looking for a job opportunity to apply my skills and further develop new ones.

----- Projects

ft_transcendence: Social network in a Club Penguin style. (5 person project) Last curriculum project, while still working on it, I've already learned:

- How to manage Client and Server communication using NodeJS.
- Real-Time socket communication in a multiplayer game (Pong with Superpowers) using Socket.io.
- Recoil atoms (Library for React) to better manage the state and re-render of Frontend components.

cub3D: Raycasting project. (Pair project)

- Recreation of Wolfenstein 3D game in C with only the help of 42's graphical library.
- Renderization of a 3D world from a 2D map using the DDA algorithm to determine where the ray hits the wall.

inception: Docker project to build a LEMP stack using only Debian images.

- The website was served using WordPress and PHP-FPM to serve a dynamic website handling multiple concurrent requests.
- Used Nginx, with SSL/TLS integration, as reverse-proxy managing and routing requests to the services.
- Integrated MariaDB as the database system.

Work Experience =

Quality Verifier@Coficab | 2020-2021

Coficab is a cable company and I worked as a Quality Verifier of the production lines. The improved skills:

- Adaptability and Resilience Working in 3 different shifts.
- Versatility Rapidly mastered all 11 different production lines due to a lack of workers in the quality department when i joined.
- · Stress Handling and Time/Task Management Managed daily shifts according to the cable production schedules of the 2-3 assigned lines.
- Tactful Communication Gave error feedback in a way that would match the colleague's personality respecting his work style.

Volunteer@Clube Escape Livre | 2020-2022

Clube Escape Livre is a brand that organizes motorsport events, luxury road and off-road tours, has it's own magazine and radio program.

I volunteered due to my passion for automobiles.

The tasks that i engaged in include route planning for the tours, checkpoint coordination, grabbed, delivered and photographed cars.

Contacts —

+351 927 794 191

davidmdg98@hotmail.com

davidmdgomes

<u>dadoming</u>

Lisboa, Portugal

Tech Stack -





Docker



Git



Typescript



React



Linux Systems

Languages -

Portuguese: Native

English: Fluent

Spanish: Moderate

Education —



Oct. 2021 - Jan. 2024

42 Lisboa

Common Core



2017 - 2020

Universidade da **Beira Interior**

Architecture (DNF)

- Website —

Link to my resume website.

